《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
你得离开柯林格小姐
You need to leave Miss Kringle alone.
我明白了
I get it now.
你是喜欢上我女人了
You got a thing for my girl.
天呐
Oh, dear.
谁派你去的
Who sent you?
你希望我去告诉邦德斯洛你发现他了吗
You want me to tell Bunderslaw that you're onto him?
我是布鲁斯・韦恩
I'm Bruce Wayne.
希德・邦德斯洛
Sid Bunderslaw.
哥谭市人民有权知道
The people of Gotham deserve to know
有个连环杀手生活在他们之中
that there's a serial killer in their midst.
我要追捕你
I'm coming after you.
他会杀掉调查他的警察
He murders the loved ones of any cop
心爱的人
who investigates him.
愿意跳支舞吗
Care to dance?
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
木浅薰    Silence    夜影章鱼X
爵士年代蓬蓬裙    DustD    草草
Kallen    艹明    最可爱的小胖子
早上好  睡得好吗
Morning. How'd you sleep?
我们真正入睡的那一小时吗
The hour we slept?
很好
Great.
饿了吗  我做了蛋饼
You hungry? I have quiche.
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
至少喝点咖啡吧
At least have some coffee.
我给你讲讲我为今天做的安排
Let me tell you about the day I have planned for us.
我想我还是走吧
I think I'm just gonna get out of here.
等等
Just wait.
昨晚过得很愉快  不是吗
We had fun last night, right?
别走
Stay.
听着  你没必要这么做的
Listen, you don't have to do this.
做什么
Do what?
昨晚在舞会上
Last night at the ball,
你确实说得天花乱坠
you talked a good game.
但还是别假装我们之间还有更多感情了
But let's not pretend this is more than what it is.
芭芭拉  我不是装的
Barbara, I'm not pretending with you.
我想要你
I want you
留下来陪我
to stay with me.
算了吧
I don't think so.
等等  等等
Just... wait, wait, wait.
放开
Let go.
好吧
Look...
我确实在伪装
I was pretending with you.
但并不是你想象的那样
But not in the way you think.
我们初遇的那晚上
The night we met....
我本来想杀掉你的
I was going to kill you.
-不好笑  -但是...
- That's not funny. - But then...
我在你身上看到了某种特质
I saw something in you,
芭芭拉  我看到了
Barbara, I saw...
真实的你
the real you.
你就是我一直在寻找的女人
You are the woman that I have been searching for.
你骗人
You're lying.
我这就放开你
I'm gonna let you go now,
你要乖乖坐下
and you're going to sit down
和我一起吃早餐
and have breakfast with me.
饿得慌
宝宝
草草
快开啊
Come on.
不
No!
那就用粗暴的方式来了
So I do it the hard way.
哥谭
第一季第二十一集
你还好吗
How are you doing?
不太好  见到哈维了吗
Been better. You seen Harvey?
没有
No.
芭芭拉有消息吗
Any word on Barbara?
还没发现她的尸体
They haven't found her body yet,
所以她有可能还活着
so there's a chance she's still alive.
你多久没睡觉了
When's the last time you slept?
不知道
I don't know.
-吃饭呢  -我不知道
- Last time you ate? - I don't know.
我知道让你睡你肯定也不会听话
I know better than to try to get you to sleep,
但你至少得吃点东西
but you really should eat something.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
吉姆
Jim...
这不是你的错
it's not your fault.
都怪我  是我向洛布施压
I did this. I pressed Loeb,
他才让食人魔找上了我
he sent the Ogre after me,
而我没有停手
and I didn't stop.
明知道会给你带来危险就够糟糕了
It was bad enough I knowingly put you in danger.
我都没想起还有芭芭拉
I didn't even think of Barbara.
那是你的工作
You were doing your job.
-但我早该知道的  -怎么可能
- But I should've known. - How?
你们已经分手了
Y-You weren't together.
难道不爱她了你也要怪自己吗
Do you blame yourself for falling out of love?
小莱  这是我的责任
Lee, it's my responsibility.
你说什么也不能改变这个事实
There's nothing you can say that changes that.
芭芭拉出了事
Whatever happens to Barbara,
那就得怪我
it's on me.
我理解
I understand.
吉姆
Jimbo!
这位是皮条客杰克
Meet Jake the JV pimp.
他在外面跟人吹牛
He's been bragging on the streets
说他知道食人魔是谁
that he knows who the Ogre is.
我跟你说了多少遍了
I keep telling you, man,
你被骗了  我什么也不知道
you been lied to; I don't know nothing.
是吗
Yeah?
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
好了
Okeydoke.
没尸体不立案  没尸体不立案
No body, no crime. No body, no crime.
没有  从来没见过他
Nope. Never seen him before.
我们认为这个人是连环杀手食人魔
We think this is a serial killer called the Ogre.
他绑架了一个女人
He's kidnapped a woman,
而且要杀掉她  除非我们先抓到他
and he's gonna kill her unless we find him first.
真遗憾
Bummer.
跟你说清楚
Just so you understand,
这位女士是我们的好朋友
the lady in question is a real good friend of ours.
那么  假如说
Supposing, for the sake of argument,
我的确见过他
I did see him before.
她值多少
What's she worth?
什么意思
你懂的
Yeah, you know,
如果要说个数的话
if you had to assign a dollar amount.
哈维  我打算在审讯方法上
Harvey, I'm about to violate departmental policy
违反一下部门政策
on interrogation techniques.
我好像看到外面有给我的甜甜圈
Think I saw some donuts outside with my name all over them.
别激动
Hey, now. C-Calm yourself.
没必要被情绪冲昏头...
There's no need to get carried...
杰克在一家叫指顶花夜总会的妓院
Jake worked as a barman at a brothel
做酒吧招待
called the Foxglove.
他说食人魔是常客  没法给我们提供位置
Said the Ogre was a regular. Can't give us a location.
因为相同的地方他们不会用两次
Yeah, 'cause they never use the same place twice.
-什么  你知道吗  -没亲眼见过
- What, you know it? - Not personally.
指顶花的档次极其高
The Foxglove is very high-class, very extreme.
你得认识人牵线搭桥才能找到
You got to know someone who knows someone.
我也许认识个人
Uh, I might know someone.
你是说企鹅吗
You talking Penguin?
你和那混蛋再走得近一点  就会受他控制
If you get any deeper with that clown, he will own you.
我没得选  芭芭拉在食人魔手上
I don't have a choice; the Ogre has Barbara.
让我去查查
Let me shake a few trees.
别心急  休息一会儿
Take the time, grab some "Z"s.
你要累死了
You're burnt!
第一个是最难的
First one was the hardest.
但那不是她的错
But it wasn't her fault.
她就是不是我要找的人
She just wasn't the one.
我也不能放她走
I also couldn't let her go.
但是这让我更下定决心
Still, it strengthened my resolve
不找到适合我的伴侣
to never stop till I found my soul mate--
能与之分享一切的人  誓不罢休
person I could share everything with.
我认为这人就是你  芭芭拉
I think that person is you, Barbara,
但我需要你的配合
but I need your help.
那么
So...
我们再来一次吧
let's begin again, shall we?
送信人
This just, uh...
刚刚送来了这个给你  布鲁斯少爷
came for you by messenger, Master Bruce.
谢谢
Thank you.
好  那...
Right, well, I'll...
那我走了
I'll just be off.
要人陪你吗
Do you want company?
给雷吉认尸吗
To identify Reggie?
不  不用了  我还是自己去吧
No, I don't think so. Best done alone.
我很遗憾  阿尔弗雷德
I'm sorry, Alfred.
我知道他是你的朋友
I know he was your friend.
这事说不通
Just doesn't make any sense.
雷吉竟然这样自杀
Reggie topping himself like that.
你说他从窗户掉下去了
You said he fell out of a window.
可能是喝了酒  失足掉下去的
He might've been drinking, lost his balance.
不  雷吉是个传奇
No, Reggie, he was a legend.
即使他喝得烂醉  也能去走钢丝
He could be blind drunk and walk a tightrope.
他的结局如何不重要了
Doesn't matter what he was like in the end.
我一定给他安排个体面的葬礼
I want to see he gets a proper send-off.
晚上见  少爷
I'll see you this evening, sir.
希望你找到你要的  小心点  塞琳娜
你老板不信任合伙人吗
What, your boss doesn't trust his partners?
这叫做尽职
It's called due diligence.
他只是要我检查一下
He just wants me to look the place over.
请吧
So look.
我还煮着肉汤呢  今天有特别的派对
I got a gravy going-- special party today.
别让我耽误你了
Don't let me keep you.
臭娘们
Piece of work.
我会把手枪放在吧台下
I'll put the pistol under the bar,
把机关枪放在点唱机后面
machine gun behind the juke.
康纳和他的人只要去拿就行
All Connor and his guy got to do is get to them.
这天终于来了
The day is finally here.
马罗尼
Maroni...
吉姆
Jim.
很高兴见到你
So lovely to see you.
何事大驾光临啊
To what do I owe this wonderful surprise?
我要知道指顶花夜总会在哪
I need to know where the Foxglove is.
还需要一封邀请函
And I need an invitation.
有人心情大好啊
Well, someone's in a mood.
你能帮我吗  一句话
Can you help me out? Yes or no.
吉姆  我很喜欢我们公平交易的关系
Jim, I do so love our give-and-take relationship.
但我开始觉得索取的总是你
But it's starting to feel a bit one-sided.
好吧
Fine.
我欠你一个人情
I'll owe you a favor.
你已经欠了一个
You already do.
那就再欠一个
Then I'll owe you another.
我明说吧
Cards on the table.
指顶花夜总会为一些达官显贵挣不少...
The Foxglove makes a lot of money for some important f...
你自以为了解我
You think you know who I am.
知道我的底线
What I'm capable of.
你根本不知道
You have no idea.
今天对我很重要
Today is an important day for me...
所以我会帮你这个忙
so I will accommodate your request.
但是  警探  你给我记好了
But, Detective, mark my words.
你欠我一个天大的人情
You owe me a big favor.
这里就是操作部
Here we have the Physical Operations department.
操作部
The Physical Operations department
负责公司后勤工作
handles logistics for the corporation,
管理我们的资产和办公场所
management of our properties, offices...
不好意思  我需要去一下洗手间
Excuse me, I need to use the restroom.
好的  韦恩先生  就在那边
Of course, Mr. Wayne. It's right here.
谢谢
Thank you.
指顶花夜总会就在五月花街的克朗代克大厦
The Foxglove is in the old Klondike Building on Mayflower.
-你搞到了门票  -没错
- You score a ticket? - Yep.
不过就一张
But only one.
我打算让你伪装成嫖客潜伏进去
I figure you go in, pose as a john,
找个由头进行搜查
find something to bust them on,
然后我们撬开他们的嘴
then we squeeze them till they talk.
派我去潜伏是高招
Smart move sending me, hmm?
你就算不穿制服也是一身警察味儿
You couldn't look more like a cop if you wore a blue uniform.
你不换身行头吗
You got something to wear?
-你还得融入环境呢  -别担心
- You, uh, are gonna need to fit in. - Don't worry.
阿尔瓦雷斯上周抓到几个人倒卖意式西服
Alvarez busted some guys smuggling Italian suits last week,
赃物送去物证室的路上
and a couple fell in my locker
不小心落了几件在我柜子里
on their way to the evidence room.
抱歉丢下你一人
I'm sorry I left you alone,
但你需要点时间思考下
but you needed time to think,
好接受这是真的
to accept that this was real.
顺便说一声  这间公寓是隔音的
This apartment is soundproofed, by the way,
所以别费劲喊了
so save your lungs.
瞧瞧我  手都抖了
Look at me. My hands are shaking.
那么多女人来来去去
That's never happened before
我都从来没手抖过
with any of the other women that I've had here.
你知道为什么吗
You know why that is?
你知道是因为什么吗
Do you know why that is?
你是个疯子
You're a psycho.
我不知道你在想什么
I don't know what you're thinking.
因为我总是能感觉出来
It's because I always somehow knew
其他人本质上不是我要的人
that deep down, the others weren't the one.
不是我要找的人
They weren't the one.
我希望你我能成  芭芭拉
I want this to work, Barbara.
你很害怕
You're scared.
没关系
It's okay.
吉姆会找到
Jim will find...
唯一会惹我生气的
The only way you're going to make me angry is
就是你说他的名字
if you mention his name.
喝了
Drink this.
是水  你脱水了
It's water. You're dehydrated.
芭芭拉  来  我要给你看件东西
Barbara, come here. I want you to see something.
芭芭拉  我爱你
Barbara, I love you.
我比其他所有人都爱你
I love you like no one has ever loved you.
但如果你想逃
But if you try to escape,
我会把你吊在天花板上宰了你
I will chain you to the ceiling and gut you.
赶紧  过来
Now come... here.
这些是...
Are those...
寻找真爱的路上
When you're looking for love,
难免遇到不少错的人
you have to kiss a lot of frogs.
不过我还是得感激她们
Still, I-I should be thankful.
是她们让我找到了你
They led me to you.
这些女人
All those women...
都死在这了吗
they died here?
你在这儿
You killed them...
杀了她们吗
here?
是的
Yes.
别紧张
Don't worry.
我会放了你的
I'm gonna set you free.
你就是我要找的人  芭芭拉
You're the one, Barbara.
你是我的真爱
You're the one.
希德・邦德斯洛
你好  布鲁斯
Hello, Bruce.
我一直在等你
I've been expecting you.
你朋友借了我的钥匙之后
Ever since your friend borrowed my key,
我就一直在等你
I've been expecting you.
连行程都取消了
Even canceled my trip.
吃饼干吗
Cookie?
我小时候
When I was a boy,
对饼干一向来者不拒
I'd always take a cookie when I had the chance.
你雇人刺杀阿尔弗雷德
You hired a man to kill Alfred.
我只是雇了你管家的老战友
I hired your guardian's comrade
去查明你究竟知道些什么
to find out what you knew.
我没想伤害任何人
I never intended harm to come to anyone.
我跟董事会说了  你的情况特殊
I told the board you were a special case,
需要提前跟你说清楚
that you need the talk early.
说清楚
The talk?
布鲁斯  当韦恩家族的成员长到一定年纪后
Bruce, when members of the Wayne family reach a certain age,
就需要了解到生活和生意的真相
some facts of life and business are explained...
韦恩集团在犯罪
Wayne Enterprises is committing serious crimes.
是的
Oh, my, yes.
这是个跨国大公司
This is a multinational corporation
在上百个行政辖区做生意
operating in hundreds of jurisdictions.
只要有利可图  违法的事我们也尽力去做
We do our best to subvert all of them if it means profits.
你承认了
So... you admit it?
和你父亲一样
Just like your father.
他也曾拿着秘密文件来  说要伸张正义
He came in with his secret files, demanding justice.
不过只是一开始
At first.
后来他就改了主意
Then he changed his mind.
你撒谎
You're lying.
你父亲后来明白了生意的真实情况
Your father came to understand the reality of this business.
他的父亲也一样
As did his father.
你也会
And as will you.
我父亲是好人
My father was a good man.
你可以过上丰衣足食的生活
You have an opportunity to live a blessed life,
这也是你父母所希望的
the life your father and mother wanted for you.
我希望你再考虑考虑
I beg you to reconsider.
抱歉
Pardon me.
卢修斯  请进
Lucius, come in.
布鲁斯・韦恩
Bruce Wayne,
这是卢修斯・福克斯  我们一位初级主管
meet one of our junior executives, Lucius Fox.
外面有个公关部的人
There's a public relations person out there
急着要找这个年轻人
desperately searching for this young man.
那快带他去吧
Then you'd best reunite them.
布鲁斯
Bruce,
别忘了你的饼干
don't forget your cookie.
听着
Now...
我要告诉你一些事
I'm going to tell you something,
听完之后  你一定要面不改色
and I'd appreciate if you kept your face perfectly still.
这里到处都是摄像头
There's cameras everywhere.
我知道  因为都是我装的
I know because I put them there.
我要说的是只能我们俩知道的大秘密
What I'm about to say must be a deep secret between you and me.
我和你父亲相熟
I knew your father well.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
他并不像公司以为的那样
He wasn't the man the company thought he was.
我不明白
I don't understand you.
布鲁斯
Bruce,
你父亲是个真正清心寡欲之人
your father was a true Stoic.
他最好的一面不为人所知
He kept his best self hidden.
我就说这么多了
That's all I'll say.
祝你好运
Good luck.
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma?
柯林...
Ms. Kri...
柯林格小姐
Ms. Kringle?
能开一下门吗
Would you open the door, please?
我...
Um, I'm...
稍等
One sec!
我需要亨德里克斯案的案卷
I need the Hendricks case files.
嗯  亨德里克斯
Um, yes. Hendricks.
等我一下
Wait right here.
亨德里克斯  亨德里克斯
Hendricks. Hendricks.
亨德里克斯  亨德里克斯  亨德里克斯
Hendricks, Hendricks, Hendricks, Hendricks.
Hendricks, Hendricks, Hendricks.
天啊
Oh, my goodness.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
斧...是事故
axe... uh, a-accidental death.
在一家金属片厂
At a sheet metal factory.
工业电锯...
Industrial saw. Just...
可怜人
Poor man.
真不知道你怎么受得了这份工作
I... I don't know how you do this job.
被死亡包围
Death all around you.
是啊  所以一定要有幽默感
Yes. One must have a sense of humor.
案卷
The-the file?
给
Yes.
尼格玛先生
Um, Mr. Nygma,
你有没有遇到汤姆...多尔蒂警官
you haven't, by chance, seen, uh, Tom... Officer Dougherty?
我们昨晚约好一起吃晚饭的
We were... supposed to have dinner last night.
他没来  这也不奇怪
He didn't show-- no surprise--
但今天他也没来上班
um, but I haven't seen him today.
我也没见到他
Me neither.
抱歉  我真的得工作了
Excuse me. I really need to get back to work.
就现在
Now.
好吧
Okay.
天啊
Oh, dear.
你确定
You're sure...
枪在那里了吗
the guns are there?
布奇亲自放的
Butch placed them himself.
你还记得下手前应该和马罗尼说什么吗
Do you remember what to say to Maroni before you do the deed?
我向来不理解为什么要在崩人前
I never saw the point in telling a man something
和他废话
right before you're gonna whack him,
不过你也不是第一个提出这要求的
but you're not the first to ask for it.
多谢迁就我
I appreciate you humoring me.
你怎么知道马罗尼一定会在今天
So how do you know Maroni's gonna be in this bar
出现在那个酒吧
on this exact day?
我关注时事
I follow current events.
声名狼藉的杀手汤米・伯恩斯今天被释放
他来了
There he is.
他娘的汤米・伯恩斯
Tommy freakin' Bones.
入狱九年
Nine years up the river,
你还变漂亮了  你这家伙
and you get better-looking, you big animal.
我知道照顾自己
Took care of myself.
我就希望你还记得
I was hoping you'd remember.
过来吧
Come over here.
你离开牢房  就来莉迪娅这儿吃饭
Listen, you leave the joint, you come to Lidia's for dinner.
这是传统
That's tradition.
欢迎回家  莉迪娅
Welcome home. Lidia!
看看谁来了
Look who's here.
欢迎来到指顶花夜总会
Welcome to the Foxglove.
今晚的娱乐节目就要开始了
The evening's entertainment is about to begin.
那看来我来得正是时候
Then I guess I'm just in time.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请注意一下  谢谢
your attention, please.
我知道你们都急切期待着今晚的
I know you have been eagerly awaiting tonight's
主要节目
main attraction.
所以请给英格丽德和加雷思一个
So, please, let's give a big Foxglove welcome
指顶花式的热烈欢迎
to Ingrid and Gareth.
哦不
Oh, no.
去他的
Hell no.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
所有人都别动
Nobody move!
特别是你俩
Especially you two!
芭芭拉
Barbara?
起来  芭芭拉
Wake up, Barbara.
醒醒
Wake up.
过来
Come here.
别哭
Don't cry.
没必要哭的  好吗
There's no need to cry. Okay?
你会杀了我
You're gonna kill me.
你希望我杀你吗
Do you want me to?
不
No!
那告诉我要去杀谁
Then tell me who to kill.
什么
Wh-What?
你还是不相信我爱你
You still don't believe I love you.
你觉得我是疯子
You think I'm crazy.
没关系
That's fine.
我看得到真相
I see the truth.
我看得到你的真相
I see your truth.
我看得出你这辈子都试图抹杀它
I see that you've spent your whole life trying to kill it,
但你做不到...
but you can't--
它太强烈了
it's too strong.
那晚你向我展示了它
You revealed it to me the other night.
我想要释放它  我想要给你自由
I want to set that free. I want to set you free.
你觉得我让你去杀人
You think that me making you murder someone
我就会喜欢上你吗
will make me like you?
简直是疯了
That's insane.
你这么说
You say that
是因为你不了解毫无畏惧的滋味
because you don't know what it is to live without fear.
但你会知道的
But you'll learn.
告诉我
Now, tell me...
你想让我杀谁
who you want me to kill,
否则  虽然我会伤心欲绝
or, though it breaks my heart,
但我会马上杀了你
I will take your life right now.
我不能
I can't.
I... I can't.
我不能
告诉我
Tell me...
去杀谁
who... to kill.
这地方你开的
You run this place?
我在找这个人
I'm looking for this man.
想逮捕我随你  我不会谈论客户的
Arrest me if you want to; I don't talk about my clients.
我给《公报》一通电话  他们就会派记者来
One call to the Gazette, they'll send a reporter down here.
我当众逮捕押送你所有的客户
I'll perp-walk each and every one of your clients
让他们都拍下来
in front of the cameras.
怎么样
How's that sound?
问萨莉吧
Talk to Sally.
你认识他
Do you know him?
你确定
You sure?
非常确定
I'm sure.
他说他叫杰森
He said his name was Jason.
很会说话
He was sweet.
我一上他的车  他就用头罩蒙住我的头
As soon as I got into his car, he pulled a hood over my head
还绑住了我的手腕
and tied my wrists.
他带我回了他的公寓
He took me back to his apartment.
给我留下了这个
That's where he did this.
我不知道他为什么放我走了
I don't know why he let me go.
什么时候的事
When was this?
-差不多九年前  -大概是第一起
- Almost nine years ago. - About a year before
凶案前一年  他是在慢慢升级
the first murder-- he was working his way up.
你怎么没报警
Why didn't you go to the police?
我报了
I did.
我是个妓女  而他是我说不上名字的有钱人
I was a hooker; he was a rich man with no name.
你还记得什么吗
Anything else you can tell us?
关于他的公寓
Anything about his apartment?
哪怕是最细微的细节也有用
The smallest detail might help.
电梯直接通向他的公寓
The elevator opened right into the apartment.
可以眺望城市
You can see out into the city.
我们在中城区
We were in midtown.
而且有个大霓虹灯标志
And there was a big neon sign
就在街对面的大楼上
on the building across the street.
我只能看到最后四个字母
I could only read the last four letters.
OYAL
O-y-a-l.
忠诚...皇家
Loyal, royal...
皇家
Royal.
哥谭皇家酒店
Gotham Royal Hotel.
是在中城区  10大道和甘斯利大街街口
That's in midtown. 10th and Gainsly.
谢谢你  萨莉
Thank you, Sally.
答应我  你找到他后
Promise me, when you find him,
别逮捕他
don't arrest him.
杀了他
Kill him.
好
You got it.
各位  私人派对
Whoa, fellas, private party.
就是来表示下敬意
Just here to pay respects.
狂野东北的康纳
Connor from the wild northeast.
法尔科内那老家伙又想怎么样
What's that old man Falcone want now?
法尔科内阁下派我来致以敬意
Don Falcone sends me with his respects,
并为您和汤米・伯恩斯
and a small gift for you
准备了薄礼一份  庆祝这个好日子
and Tommy Bones on this happy day.
奇克
Cheech.
原谅我这么多疑
Forgive my suspicious nature.
当然  小心驶得万年船
Of course. Can't be too careful.
来  拿给我看
Come here. Let me see this.
马德雷瓷罐
Madre di Dios.
我最喜欢了
My favorite.
告诉法尔科内  多谢他这番心意
You tell Falcone I appreciate the gesture.
法尔科内阁下知道这日子的特殊性
Don Falcone knew it was a special occasion.
我们可以喝一杯  莉迪娅
We got time for a drink. Lidia!
准备干净杯子
Clean glasses, please.
另外还有话要捎给您
The gift comes with a message.
是吗  什么话
Oh, yeah? What's that?
他要告诉您  决定杀您
He wants you to know that it wasn't easy
并非易事
for him to decide to kill you.
该死
Son of a bitch.
但生意归生意
But business is business.
能相信吗
You believe it?
你们都卡枪了
You both jammed.
如果这还不算神迹  我都不知道怎么才算了
If that ain't a sign from God, I don't know what.
-求您  -闭嘴
- Please... - Shut your mouth!
你去给法尔科内阁下捎去我的话
You're gonna take don Falcone a message from me.
让他知道你搞砸了
You're gonna let him know that you messed up...
告诉他我跟他没完
...and you're gonna let him know that I'm coming for him.
不过  你不非得活着也能捎这个信儿
Of course, you don't need to be alive to tell him that.
汤米  请吧
Tommy, do the honors.
等等
Wait...
朋克族  坏男孩*
*All you punks and all you teds
民族阵线  爆炸头*
*National Front and Natti dreds
时髦人物  摇滚迷  嬉皮士  光头党*
*Mods, rockers, hippies and skinheads...
康纳搞砸了
Connor blew it.
马罗尼还活着
Maroni's still alive.
这酒太没滋味了
This is flat.
你没听到吗
Did you not hear me?
马罗尼还活着
Maroni is still alive.
你得赶快离开哥谭
You got to get out of town.
错过精彩的场面吗
And miss all the fun?
你早知道
You knew.
你给他下套
You set him up.
你藏枪之前  我把撞针都拔了
I took the firing pins out of the guns before you hid them.
这是我从马罗尼那儿学来的
A spin on a trick I learned from Maroni.
但你本可杀掉马罗尼的
But you could have had Maroni dead.
是啊  但那样我还是得在法尔科内之下
True, but I still would've been under Falcone's thumb,
而这让我越来越无法忍受了
and that... has grown intolerable.
不  我宁可让马罗尼活着
No, I'd much rather Maroni be alive,
一心想复仇
and out for blood.
可惜啊  多尔蒂警官  她会想你去哪了
Alas, Officer Dougherty, she's gonna wonder where you went.
写封信吧
Perhaps a letter.
跟她道别  给她句忠告
You could say good-bye, give her some advice.
或许让她
Something that might lead her
今后能做出更好的选择
to make better choices in the future, hmm?
皇家
吉姆
Jim?
这里没人
Place is empty.
但你该过来看看
But there's something you should see.
看到什么跟芭芭拉有关的东西了吗
You see anything that connects to Barbara?
或许她没来过
Maybe she was never here.
不  她来过
No, she was here.
我还能闻到她的香水味儿
I can still smell her perfume.
我们会找到他的
Hey, we're gonna find this guy,
但你得做好心理准备
but you need to prepare yourself...
我们或许赶不及救下她
...that we might not be in time to save her.
这不可以
That is not an option.
这很有可能
It's the most likely option.
喂
Hello.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon,
应该是你触响了警报吧
I assume you are the one who triggered the alarm.
你个混蛋  芭芭拉呢
You son of a bitch. Where's Barbara?
当然是跟我在一起
With me, of course.
如果你敢伤害她
If you've hurt her...
她十分安全
She's as safe as milk.
比跟你在一起的时候安全多了
Safer than she ever was when she was with you.
你这话什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
她不需要你的保护  吉姆
She doesn't need your protection, Jim.
她从来都不需要
Fact is, she never did.
回见了
I'll see you around.
等等
Wait.
他在开车
He was driving.
如果他有脑子就开去大溪地
To Tahiti if he's smart.
有个杂音  是吧
Yeah, there was a noise, right?
敲击声  像是在过桥
A thumping, like he was going over a bridge.
我好像听到了火车笛
You know, I heard, uh, a horn, like a train horn.
哪座桥有火车
Okay, so, which bridge has a train?
该死  白十字  去州北的火车
Damn. Um... Whitecross, but that's the upstate train.
州北
Upstate.
她父母住那里
It's where her parents live.
芭芭拉  求你了
Barbara, please.
怎么回事啊
What's happening?
你们的女儿终于觉醒了
What's happening is your daughter is finally waking up.
求你
Please.
芭芭拉  我们这是为了你
Barbara, we're doing this for you.
吉姆
Jim?
芭芭拉
Barbara.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你不该来的
You're not supposed to be here.
他在哪
Where is he?
放下
Drop it.
放下刀  否则我开枪了
Drop the knife, or I'll shoot.
稍施加点压力  她就会血如泉涌
Just an ounce of pressure, and she'll split right open.
我可不希望那样  你呢
I don't want that. Do you want that?
没事的  芭芭拉
It's gonna be all right, Barbara.
没事的
It's gonna be all right.
如果你真在乎她
If you cared about this woman,
你就根本不会来追查我
you never would have come after me.
我比你要更爱她
I love her more than you ever did.
放下刀
Drop the knife.
割开她喉咙的不是我
Won't be me that slits her throat.
警探  那是你
Detective, that's gonna be you.
-放下刀  -吉姆  求你
- Drop it. - Jim, please.
放我们走吧
Just leave us alone.
混蛋
Hey, jerk-o!
芭芭拉
Barbara?
他死了
He's dead?
嗯  他死了
Yeah. He's dead.
没事了
It's gonna be okay.
看着我  芭芭拉
Look at me. Barbara?
没事了
It's gonna be okay.
阿尔弗雷德  我还没问你呢
Alfred, I never asked you.
昨天去安葬雷吉怎么样
How was it yesterday, seeing Reggie?
我并不想再回忆一遍  布鲁斯少爷
Not really, uh, an experience I'd care to repeat, Master Bruce.
不过  我所认识的雷吉早就不在了
But then again, the Reggie I knew died years ago.
阿尔弗雷德  我对你有所隐瞒
Alfred, I haven't been honest with you.
你受伤之后
After you were hurt,
塞琳娜和我去找雷吉了
Selina and I went looking for Reggie.
我们找到了他
We found him.
是吗
Did you, now?
他没有跳楼  也没摔下去
He didn't jump or fall.
是塞琳娜把他推下去了
Selina pushed him.
她为什么要那么做
And why did she do that?
雷吉是一个叫希德・邦德斯洛的人派来的
Reggie was sent here by a man named Sid Bunderslaw.
邦德斯洛在韦恩集团工作
Bunderslaw works for Wayne Enterprises.
雷吉供出了他的名字
Reggie gave us the name,
但又说会去告诉邦德斯洛我们做了什么
but said he was gonna tell Bunderslaw what we were doing.
这样啊
I see.
还有呢
And the rest?
慈善舞会
The charity ball--
应该是为接近邦德斯洛先生吧
presumably to have access to Mr. Bunderslaw.
塞琳娜偷了他办公室保险柜的钥匙
Selina stole the key to his office safe.
我今天去了  里面是空的
I went there today. It was empty.
但邦德斯洛在那儿等着我
But Bunderslaw was waiting for me.
-他做了什么  -没什么
- What did he do? - Nothing.
他做了什么
What did he do?!
没什么
Nothing!
但他说我父亲和我祖父
But he said that my father and grandfather
都知道公司在做违法的事
knew about the illegal things that the company was doing,
却选择...
and chose...
他们选择了沉默
They chose to stay quiet.
你父亲是个好人
Your father was a good man.
我知道
I know.
但好人也有秘密
But even good men have secrets.
他来了
There he is.
-就是他  -干得好
- That guy right there. - Yeah, nice work.
干得好
Yeah, nice work.
恭喜  你成了英雄
Congratulations. You're a hero.
也就这一时吧
Yeah, it won't last.
明天他们就又恨我了
Tomorrow, they'll go back to hating me.
那我会提醒他们的
Well, then I'll remind them.
昨天你只是想帮忙
Yesterday, you were trying to help.
我却听不进去  对不起
I couldn't hear it. I'm sorry.
我绝不会试图改变你的  吉姆
I would never try to change you, Jim.
你的使命感  也是我喜欢你的一部分原因
Your sense of mission-- it's part of what I love about you.
我以为是因为我帅得没天理呢
I thought it was my devastating good looks.
我说笑呢
That's a joke.
我是害怕
I was scared.
我怕芭芭拉会受伤
Scared that Barbara would get hurt
而你会责备自己先来保护我
and you would blame yourself for protecting me first,
而我们的感情也会因此破碎
and then whatever we had would die.
那并不英勇  只是自私
It wasn't heroic. It was selfish.
小莱  我爱你
Lee, I love you.
不是她
Not her.
如果让我再来一次  我也会先保护你
If I had to do it again, I'd still protect you first.
你干什么了
What did you do?
握刀刃来着
Uh, grabbed a... knife by the blade.
当然了
Of course you did.
让我看看
Let me see.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我收到一封多尔蒂警官的信
I got a letter from Officer Dougherty.
他离开哥谭了
He left town.
"别等我了  好好享受人生吧
"Don't wait around for me. Go have some fun,
或许等我回来会再找你"
and maybe I'll give you a call when I get back."
一堆废话
Blah, blah, blah.
都不当面跟我说
Couldn't even tell me to my face.
我为什么总选这些混蛋啊
I mean, why do I keep picking creeps?
有时候男人的本意在字里行间之外
Sometimes with men, you need to read between the lines.
有时候男人的烦心事  得喝酒忘记
Sometimes with men, you need a drink.
日安  尼格玛先生
Good day, Mr. Nygma.
尼格玛
字里行间啊
Read between the lines.
大家听好
Everybody listen up!
刚刚得到消息  法尔科内城里
Just got wind of three separate attacks
三处不同地点的生意遭到袭击
on Falcone businesses in different parts of town.
据传是马罗尼干的
Word is it's Maroni.
即刻起  所有休假取消
As of right now, all leaves are canceled,
所有警员都要值勤
and all units are called in for active duty.
枪战开始了  各位
We're in a shooting war, people.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com